DAN KLEIN: The last thing we're going
to talk about today is local search.
So far, the search logarithms we've
talked about were not local.
They had a fringe where you were
trying some particular
branch of the tree.
And if that didn't work out, you went
back to the fringe and you tried your
other backup strategies, right?
And the search algorithms vary based on
how you manage that fringe, but the
fringe was always there
as a safety net.
In local search, you don't
have this safety net.
You've got one position that you're
currently at, and you are trying to
hill climb in some way.
And you can think about this,
you are this robot here.
You are at some point in this space of
possible solutions, and you're trying
to take the solution you have
and improve it bit by bit.
And just like this robot, you might know
that out there somewhere is the
best possible goal you could get to.
But of course all you can see is a
couple feet forward in the mountain.
That's what local search is like.
So where tree search kept track of an
unexplored alternative on the fringe,
and that ensured completeness, local
search, you improve the single option
until you can't make it better.
You have a new idea of the
successor function.
The successor function now does not
take a plan and extend the plan.
Instead, it takes a complete
assignment of some kind
and modifies it.
So your successor function
is more about
modification than about extension.
So here's an example, again, of the two
node coloring problem, and all of
its possible successors.
In general, local search is much faster
and much more memory efficient
than a tree search, or a graph search
that keeps track of a fringe.
But on the other hand, it's going to
lose the completeness and optimality
guarantees that came from having a
fringe, and operate it in a way that
was sensitive to costs.
So that's your trade off.